So we're back to our blog.
回到我们的博客页面
Here what we want to do is in the content section,
这里我们要来关注一下 content 内容区域
I think it'd be fun to make a photo gallery,
如果把它变成一个照片相册应该不错
and CSS grid is set up perfectly to do such a thing.
而且正好可以发挥 CSS grid 的优势
Because as you can see I've already got set up my two by
你可以看到这里我已经搭建好了一个
two grid which can easily become a photo gallery.
2 X 2 的网格 它很适合用来做图片相册
So let's look to see how I nested this grid inside of our larger grid.
我们来看一看如何将一个 grid 嵌套进另一个更大的 grid 容器中的
We have one grid which has our header,
我们有一个 grid 包含了 header
blog post, content, footer.
blog post content 以及 footer 区域
Then in the content we have a second nested grid.
然后在 content 中 我们有第二个嵌套的 grid
Here's what this looks like in the HTML.
这是它们对应的 HTML 代码
Inside of content I have the div with the id nested grid.
在 content 中有一个id 属性为 nestedGrid 的 div
Then inside of nested grid,
在 nestedGrid 内部
I've placed four elements each has their own id,
我放置了 4 个元素 每个元素有一个自己的 id
and shares the class, "photoBox".
同时有一个共同的类名 'photoBox'
Up here in "style",
在 style 标签中
we can see I've set up the nested grid to be display grid,
我设置了 nestedGrid 的 display 属性为 grid
and then I've just broken up the available space, the columns,
然后我们通过给行与列分别设置
and rows by 50 percent which is what gives us a four area grid.
50% 来将区域分成 4 个部分
Right now I'm choosing to explicitly set the size of each square using width and height.
到目前为止 我选择了显式的设置每个方块的宽度和高度
But say for example,
但是如果
you want something a little wider,
你想要容器更宽一些的话
the grid will adjust.
grid 也会自动适应调整
So we see that the div with the id "one" will be our top left box.
这里我们可以看到 id 为 one 的 div 被放置在了左上角的区域
So let's try to put a picture in there.
我们来放置一张图片在里面
We would say, "one, background-image: URL."
设置它的 background-image 属性
This is the path that I believe our picture is in,
路径设置为我们放置的图片路径
"images/waterfall.jpg" So we see it's the coming in there.
"images/waterfall.jpg" 好了 图片出现了
But I want it to size itself differently, so we'll say,
不过这里我想要调整一下它的尺寸
"background-size", let's try, "cover"
设置 background-size 为 cover 属性
it's a little better but not totally what I'm looking for.
看起来好了一些 不过不是我想要的结果
"Contain", I like that enough to leave it for now.
我们这里还是采用 contain
So let's go ahead and try to add a second image to our gallery by saying,
现在我们继续来给相册添加第二张图片
"two" and I'll just copy and paste for quickness here.
这里直接简单的复制和粘贴一遍
Let's see I think there's one called, "still-water".
然后换一张图片 换成 'styllWater'
So this is a naming thing.
这里名称弄错了
You can see here what I really want is still-water.
我真正想要的应该是 still-water
So now we have a little grid coming together.
现在我们已经有了一些组合的 grid
Let's go ahead and do the same for three and four,
我们对 three 和 four 做相同的事情
which are going to be light and night.
放置 light 和 night 图片
So here what I'm doing is I'm just changing the path so that it's a different picture.
这里要做的就是简单改变图片的路径 放置进去不同的图片
So I want this to be my picture which has the path light.jpg and this to be night.jpg.
我们将图片路径改为 light.jpg 和 night.jpg
Now, when we refresh,
现在 我们刷新页面
we see we have our grid.
好了 出现了
Now, there's a couple of things here.
这里我们还有一些要做的事情
One is I really want some more room between these.
第一件事情是我希望它们之间能有一些空隙
So if you remember we can come up to our nested grid and we can
如果你记得的话 我们可以在 nestedGrid 中
use "grid-gap" to give a little space.
使用 grid-gap 属性来添加间隙
Now that I look at it I'm interested to see what would happen if we split it up a
现在 我想再试着看看如果我们采用不同的布局方式会怎样
little differently like what would it mean to do 70-30 columns, not great.
比如将列设置为 70-30 的模式
So here you can see we have nested our CSS grids.
现在你可以看到我们有了一个嵌套的 CSS 网格
We have our main grid which is setting up the layout of the entire page.
我们有一个主要的网格 它搭建出了我们页面的主要布局结构
Then within one of the sections here the content section,
然后在 content 内容区域中
we've created a second grid which is holding these four images.
我们创建了第二个网格系统用于放置这些图片
In our HTML, we could see it literally it's
在 HTML 代码中 我们可以很直观的看见
just nesting these elements inside of each other.
它只是嵌套了一些元素在里面
The top element is the, "container".
顶部的元素是 container
Everything that's inside of here is the main grid.
在它内部是我们主要的网格系统
We see our header,
有 header 元素
blog posts, content, footer.
blog posts content 以及 footer 元素
Now if we go into content,
在 content 内部
we see that we have our nested grid,
有一个嵌套的网格系统
and inside our nested grid we have the four elements that make it up.
在它内部有 4 个元素
Now within the grid itself remember you could do everything in a nested grid,
记住 在嵌套网格中你也可以做任何你想要的事情
you could do an irregular grid.
你可以做一个不规则的网格
So if I switched the order you'll see the picture switch order.
如果我改变它们的顺序的话 你可以看见图片顺序也会改变
If I wanted to bring them back in closer together,
如果我想要它们挨得更近一些的话
we can simply go to the nested grid,
我可以简单的设置 nestedGrid 中
"grid-gap" and make it less.
的 grid-gap 属性来完成它
Now we have them nice and compact in.
现在它们就距离很近了
This is an example of using nested grids in CSS to create elegant blog page layouts.
这就是使用 CSS grid 创建博客页面结构的例子